Guide to the Maynard Mack Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Alexander Pope Research and Writing, circa 1936-1993; Series III; 36.1; (74 boxes) + 1 broadside folder
  - Pope MS: Rawson, undated (Box 68)
  - Harthbury MSS, undated (Box 68)
  - Epistle to Bathurst, undated (Box 68)
  - AP: Lost and Apocryphal MSS, 1968-1971 (Box 68)
  - Pope MS: Barrett, undated (Box 68)
  - Essay on Criticism, undated (Box 68)
  - Pope MSS: General, undated (Box 68)
  - Other Projects [empty], undated (Box 68)
  - Pope Prose: Letter to a Noble Lord, 1956 (Box 68)
  - Pope Prose: Memoirs of Scriblerus, undated (Box 68)
  - Pope Prose: Art of Sinking, undated (Box 68)
  - Pope Prose: Letter to a Noble Lord, Proper Reply... [empty], undated (Box 68)
  - Pope's edition of Shakespeare, undated (Box 68)
  - Pope Prose: A True and Faithful Narrative, undated (Box 68)
  - Pope Prose: Shakespeare Preface, undated (Box 69)
  - Pope's Prose: General, 1971 (Box 69)
  - Jacobean Shakespeare Notes, undated (Box 69)
  - Alexander Pope Biography
    - Chapter I, 1973-1981 (Box 69)
    - Chapter II: Ribbon Copy, undated (Box 69)
    - Chapter III: Ribbon Copy, undated (Box 69)
    - Chapter III: Rough Copy (AP Bio), 1982 (Box 69)
    - Chapter IV: Ribbon Copy, undated (Box 69)
    - Chapter IV: Rough Copy (AP Bio), undated (Box 69)
    - Chapter V: Ribbon Copy, undated (Box 70)
    - Chapter V: Rough Copy, undated (Box 70)
    - Chapter VI: Ribbon Copy, 1985 (Box 70)
    - Chapter VI: Rough Copy, 1982 (Box 70)
    - Chapter VII: Ribbon Copy, undated (Box 70)
    - Chapter VII: Rough Copy, undated (Box 70)
    - Chapter VIII: Ribbon Copy, 1984 (Box 71)
    - Chapter VIII: Rough Copy, 1983 (Box 71)
    - Chapter IX: Ribbon Copy, 1982 (Box 71)
    - Chapter IX: Rough Copy, 1982 (Box 71)
  - Miscellaneous photocopied correspondence manuscripts and Steinberg paper, 1980 (Box 71)
  - MHRA: Appraisal, Johnson/Pope, 1983 (Box 71)
  - Handwritten notes, undated (Box 72)
  - Materials 'to work with' [and loose notes of no value], undated (Box 72)
  - Pope 1988 [mostly stuff to be filed], undated (Box 72)
  - Published articles, undated; 2 (Box 72)
  - Pope: Poetry: Its Character
    - Maine and Scriblerian, 1979-1987 (Box 72)
    - Loose material (Box 72)
  - Pope and Others: Unpublished Letters
    - Pope: Correspondence not in Sherburn, undated (Box 72)
    - Projects for Maine, undated (Box 72)
  - Correspondence
    - Themes in AP Correspondence, undated (Box 73)
  - Miscellaneous collected notes, undated; 3 (Box 73)
  - Card Files
    - Index of Names, AP MSS, undated (Box 74)
    - Garden and City Index; Tabs and Garden Can be Used for AP Biog. Index, undated (Box 74)
    - Garden and City: Index with Reversible Cards, undated (Box 74)
    - Box for AP Biography Index with Tabs, undated (Box 74)
    - Garden and City, Etc., undated (Box 75)
    - Pope Notes to be returned to files, undated (Box 76)
    - Untitled [Pope related], circa 1979 (Box 77)
    - Garden and City Negatives, Plus Some Not Used, undated (Box 78)
    - Pope's Opinion on Men and Books, undated (Box 79)
    - General Popiana: Pope's Books, Pope Criticism (1688-1944), undated (Box 80)
    - Pope Criticism, undated (Box 81)
    - Pope's Works (1733-1751), undated (Box 82)
    - Popiana; Griffith Corrections; [?]Corrections, undated (Box 83)
    - Sherburn Card Collection - I (1704-1725), undated (Box 83)
    - Sherburn Card Collection - II (1726-1734), undated (Box 84)
    - Sherburn Card Collection - III (1735-1744, misc.), undated (Box 84)
    - Pope's Letters Sh. i-ii, undated (Box 84)
    - Pope's Letters sh. iii-iv, undated (Box 84)
  - Last and Greatest Art Orginals, undated; 14 (Box 85)
  - "Last and Greatest Art Originals", undated; 2 (Box 86 Oversize)
  - Alexander Pope Biography, page proofs [formerly Bound Bundle 1], undated (Box 87)
  - Alexander Pope Biography, page proofs [formerly Bound Bundle 2], 1984; 4 (Box 87)
  - Alexander Pope Biography, page proofs [formerly Bound Bundle 3], undated; 4 (Box 88)
  - Alexander Pope Biography, page proofs [formerly Bound Bundle 4], 1985; 4 (Box 88)
  - Dissertation by Maynard Mack
    - The Intellectual Background of Alexander Pope's Essay on Man: typescript, 1936 (Box 89)
  - The Prose Works of Alexander Pope, edited by Norman Ault
    - Vol. 1: The Earlier Works, 1711-1720, 1936 (Box 89)
  - The Twickenham Edition of the Poems of Alexander Pope, General Editor: John Butt, some volumes annotated by Mack
    - Vol. 1: Pastoral Poetry and An Essay on Criticism, edited by E. Audra and Aubrey Williams, 1961 (Box 90)
    - Vol. 1: Pastoral Poetry and An Essay On Criticism, edited by E. Audra and Aubrey Williams, 1961 (Box 90)
    - Vol. 2: The Rape of the Lock, edited by Geoffrey Tillotson, 1940 (Box 90)
    - Vol. 2: The Rape of the Lock and other poems, edited by Geoffrey Tillotson, 1962 (Box 91)
    - Vol. 3, i: An Essay on Man, edited by Maynard Mack, 1964 (Box 91)
    - Vol. 3, ii: Epistles to Several Persons, edited by F. W. Bateson, 1951 (Box 91)
    - Vol. 4: Imitations of Horace, edited by John Butt, 1961 (Box 92)
    - Vol. 5: The Dunciad, edited by James Sutherland, 1943 (Box 92)
    - Vol. 5: The Dunciad, edited by James Sutherland, 1963 (Box 92)
    - Vol. 6: Minor Poems, edited by Norman Ault and John Butt, 1954 (Box 93)
    - Vol. 7: Translations of Homer, The Iliad I-IX, edited by Maynard Mack, 1967 (Box 93)
    - Vol. 8: Translations of Homer, The Iliad X-XXIV, edited by Maynard Mack, 1967 (Box 94)
    - Vol. 9: Translations of Homer, The Odyssey I-XII, edited by Maynard Mack, 1967 (Box 94)
    - Vol. 10: Translations of Homer, The Odyssey XIII-XXIV, edited by Maynard Mack, 1967 (Box 94)
    - Vol. 11: Index Volume, edited by Maynard Mack [2 c], 1969 (Box 95)
  - Books by Maynard Mack
    - The Garden and The City: Retirement and Politics in the Later Poetry of Pope, 1731-1743, 1969 (Box 95)
    - Alexander Pope: A Life, 1986 (Box 95)
  - Lists of illustrations and prints, written on cardboard, undated; 2 (Box 96 Oversize)
  - Maps, reproductions, undated (Box 96 Oversize)
  - Prints, reproductions, undated (Box 96 Oversize)
  - "Satirical prints," reproductions, undated (Box 96 Oversize)
  - Map of Berkshire, reproduction, undated (Box 97 Oversize)
  - Reproductions of research material, undated (Box 97 Oversize)
  - Outline of Alexander Pope's life, 1709-1710, undated (Box 98 Oversize)
  - Drafts of Maynard Mack's editions of Alexander Pope's poems, undated (Box 98 Oversize)
  - Maps, reproductions, undated (Box 99 Broadside)
- Other Teaching Files, 1941-1973, 1993; Series IV; 3.6; (9 boxes)
  Series IV is comprised of files relating to various English literature courses that Mack taught.
  - English 142: Student Papers
    - English 142, 1960-1967 (Box 100)
    - Problems for 142, undated (Box 100)
    - English 143, 1966-1970; 2 (Box 100)
    - Hour Lectures, 1941-1942 (Box 100)
  - Homer, undated (Box 100)
  - Virgil - Translations and General, 1941-1965 (Box 100)
  - Milton, undated (Box 100)
  - Pastorals to Eloisa, 1952 (Box 100)
  - Prior, undated (Box 100)
  - Rape of the Lock: Predecessors and Cognates, undated (Box 100)
  - Rape of the Lock, 1966-1969 (Box 100)
  - Dryden: Criticism, 1969 (Box 101)
  - Dryden and Boileau, 1944 (Box 101)
  - Classical Tradition, 1941-1955 (Box 101)
  - Essay on Criticism, 1960-1961 (Box 101)
  - Baroque, 1957 (Box 101)
  - Criticism: 17th English, 1944-1945 (Box 101)
  - Criticism: 17th French, undated (Box 101)
  - Ancients and Moderns, undated (Box 101)
  - Prose Style: esp. Ciceronian vs. Senecan, undated (Box 101)
  - Scriblerus, 1966 (Box 101)
  - Waller and Denham, undated (Box 101)
  - Rochester's Poems, undated (Box 101)
  - Dryden: Religious Poems, 1942 (Box 101)
  - Dryden: Shorter Poems, 1959 (Box 101)
  - Dryden: Political Poems, 1965 (Box 101)
  - Eleonora, undated (Box 101)
  - Swift: Tale, undated (Box 102)
  - Gulliver's Travels, 1955 (Box 102)
  - Swift's Shorter Pieces, 1963 (Box 102)
  - Swift's Poems, 1960 (Box 102)
  - Addison: Spectator, 1941 (Box 102)
  - Beggar's Opera, undated (Box 102)
  - Essay on Man, 1960-1962 (Box 102)
  - Latin Satirists, undated (Box 102)
  - English Satirists, undated (Box 102)
  - The Role of Satirist, 1973 (Box 102)
  - MLA Paper: Satirist and Society, undated (Box 102)
  - The Portraits, 1972 (Box 103)
  - The Latin Contexts, 1967 (Box 103)
  - The Couplet: Arbuthnot, 1962 (Box 103)
  - Dunciad 1743, 1959-1960 (Box 103)
  - The Donne Imitations, undated (Box 103)
  - Horatian Poems as a Whole, undated (Box 103)
  - Selecta Poemata 1740, undated (Box 103)
  - General Projects, undated (Box 103)
  - Plans and Outlines for Critical Book on Pope, undated (Box 103)
  - Landscape in Poetry, undated (Box 103)
  - P and B: Essay on Man - Moral Essays, undated (Box 103)
  - P and B: the Satires, undated (Box 103)
  - P and B: the Dunciad, undated (Box 103)
  - Poetry and Society: Pope II, undated (Box 103)
  - Poetry and Society: the New Philosophy, undated (Box 103)
  - Poetry and Society: the New Sciences, undated (Box 103)
  - Poetry and Society: the New Politics, undated (Box 103)
  - Poetry and Society: the New Religion, undated (Box 103)
  - Poetry and Society: the Poet and the Social Audience, undated (Box 103)
  - Poetry and Society: the Poet and the Cultural Ideal (the New Man), undated (Box 103)
  - Poetry as Form: Pope III, undated (Box 103)
  - Poetry as Form: the Poetic Traditions Donne, Milton, Dryden, Jonson, undated (Box 103)
  - Pope and Montaigne: Pascal, undated (Box 103)
  - Poetry as Form: Role of Allusion, undated (Box 103)
  - Poetry as Form: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 103)
  - Poetry as Form: Rhetoric and Poetic Theory, undated (Box 103)
  - Poetry as Form: Versification et. al., undated (Box 103)
  - Diction, undated (Box 104)
  - Poetry and Speech, undated (Box 104)
  - Genres and Criticism, undated (Box 104)
  - Pope's Realism, undated (Box 104)
  - Pope's Reading, undated (Box 104)
  - Levels of Style, undated (Box 104)
  - Augustan Poetic Subject Matter, undated (Box 104)
  - Literature and Other Arts: All Periods, undated (Box 104)
  - Relation of Poems to Letters: Reminiscences, Echoes, undated (Box 104)
  - Pope's Verse Style: Coll. Essays on Pope (empty), undated (Box 104)
  - On Pope's Style and Evolution (empty), undated (Box 104)
  - Auden Project, undated (Box 104)
  - Problems in Prose, undated (Box 104)
  - Pope in Latin, Greek, Hebrew, Polyglot, undated (Box 104)
  - Rig Veda, undated (Box 104)
  - Mahabharata, undated (Box 104)
  - Various Translated Foreign Texts [folders 1-6], undated; 6 (Box 104)
  - Various Translated Foreign Texts [folders 7-16], 10 (Box 105)
  - Various Translated Foreign Texts [folder 17] (Box 106)
  - Literature I, undated (Box 106)
  - DSP: Division I, 1958 (Box 106)
  - Old Testament: Introductory, 1954-1955 (Box 106)
  - Old Testament: General, undated (Box 106)
  - Genesis, Exodus, Judges, 1956 (Box 106)
  - Ruth, Esther, Jonah, 1958 (Box 106)
  - Psalms, Song of Songs, Ecclesiastes, 1955 (Box 106)
  - Amos, Hosea, Joel, Deuteronomy, Isaiah, Ezekiel, 1958 (Box 106)
  - Job, undated (Box 106)
  - New Testament, undated (Box 106)
  - Oedipus, undated (Box 106)
  - Prometheus, 1966 (Box 106)
  - Antigone, 1958 (Box 106)
  - Euripides: Hippolytus, 1956 (Box 106)
  - Agamemnon, 1955 (Box 106)
  - Plato, 1956 (Box 106)
  - Middle Ages, 1956 (Box 107)
  - Dante, 1958 (Box 107)
  - Othello, 1956 (Box 107)
  - Antony and Cleopatra, undated (Box 107)
  - Homer, 1973 (Box 107)
  - Virgil, 1993 (Box 107)
  - Milton, 1956-1959 (Box 107)
  - Milton: Lecture on, undated (Box 108)
  - Pope, 1967 (Box 108)
  - Tom Jones, 1949 (Box 108)
  - Candide, 1959 (Box 108)
  - Don Juan, 1959 (Box 108)
  - Goethe, 1957 (Box 108)
  - Moby Dick, 1959 (Box 108)
  - T.S. Eliot, 1955 (Box 108)
  - Eliot Lectures, 1947-1954 (Box 108)
  - DSP: Last Lecture, 1957 (Box 108)
- Professional Papers and Other Research Material, 1950-1997; Series V; 11.97; (25 boxes) + 6 reels, 1 broadside folder
  Series V consists of files relating broadly to Mack's various other professional and scholarly activities.
  - TCV Series -- Professional (Box 109)
    - P-H New TCV, undated (Box 109)
  - Shoestring Press Professional
    - Publishing Marginal Books, English Publishing, undated (Box 109)
    - Fabian: Pope and Lucretius, undated (Box 109)
    - Shoestring: Texts and Contexts, undated (Box 109)
    - Untitled folder, undated (Box 109)
  - Lectures, Professional
    - Current Duties, undated (Box 109)
    - Yale Review, undated (Box 109)
  - Copyright, undated (Box 109)
  - Elizabethan Club
    - Lizzie: MM President 1986-87, undated (Box 109)
    - Elizabethan Club: New Arrival Performance, undated (Box 109)
  - American Society for 18th c. Studies
    - Society for 18th c. Studies, undated (Box 110)
    - Savile Club, undated (Box 110)
  - Northeast American Society for 18th c. Studies
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, elections, undated (Box 110)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Professional, undated (Box 110)
  - National Humanities Center, undated (Box 110)
  - Wesleyan Fielding, undated (Box 110)
  - International Association of University Professors of English, Professional
    - I.A.U.P.E., undated (Box 110)
    - M.H.R.A., undated (Box 110)
    - Lausanne Iaupe, undated (Box 110)
    - Connotations, undated (Box 110)
    - GS Newsletter, undated (Box 110)
  - Shakespeare Association of America
    - Unidentified papers, undated (Box 110)
    - American Society for Theatre Research, undated (Box 110)
    - Shakespeare Quarterly, undated (Box 110)
  - International Shakespeare Association, undated (Box 111)
  - American Shakespeare Theatre, undated (Box 111)
  - English-Speaking Union, undated (Box 111)
  - Public Broadcasting Association, Professional
    - PBA - 19 December, undated (Box 111)
    - P.B.A., undated (Box 111)
    - Unidentified papers, undated (Box 111)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation
    - Professional MacArthur Awards, undated (Box 111)
  - National Public Radio, undated (Box 112)
  - Recommendations, Professional (empty), undated (Box 112)
  - Recommendations, Professional
    - Foster Bam, undated (Box 112)
    - A - F, undated (Box 112)
  - Recommendations, Professional
    - G - O, undated (Box 112)
  - J. G. Gardner, undated (Box 113)
  - Recommendations, Professional
    - P - Z, undated (Box 113)
  - Contracts: Norton, P-H, Hayden, 1950-1993 (Box 114)
  - Contracts: Miscellaneous, 1963-1997 (Box 114)
  - Reviews: Everybody's Shakespeare, 1993-1994 (Box 115)
  - Pope Letters; 1987, undated (Box 115)
  - The 'New Shakespeare' Poem, 1985 (Box 115)
  - The Cutting Edge: Review of Quilligan at NHC, undated (Box 115)
  - Giamatti, Bart, 1989 (Box 115)
  - Everybody's Shakespeare, undated (Box 115)
  - [Receptions?] at Gauss Awards and L.A. Times Awards, 1986 (Box 115)
  - AP 300th: Efforts to Pieces, 1987 (Box 115)
  - Haskins Lectures, 1983-1992 (Box 115)
  - The Last and Greatest Art, 1990 (Box 115)
  - Review of Wallace Jackson MS, 1981 (Box 115)
  - Collected in Himself, 1984 (Box 115)
  - Literary Criticism Register, undated (Box 115)
  - WNET Gala: Speech, undated (Box 115)
  - BA Shakespeare, 1977-1979 (Box 115)
  - NPR program: Elizabeth's England, 1977 (Box 115)
  - Dying: My Words, undated (Box 116)
  - MM: Remarks at Festschroft Party (DC Party), undated (Box 116)
  - Gays' Letter to the Blount Sisters, undated (Box 116)
  - Preface to Proceedings of the Shakespeare Association: Washington, 1976 (Box 116)
  - AP Letter to John Caryll, Jr., 1976 (Box 116)
  - The Vanbrugh Letters, undated (Box 116)
  - Review for MLA of Radat on Rape of the Lock Materials for "Limits and Allusion" Papers, undated (Box 116)
  - Nal English Interviews, 1978 (Box 116)
  - Introduction of Saul Bellows, undated (Box 116)
  - Teachers' Lecture Materials (Houston), undated (Box 116)
  - Towson Commencement Addres - LA state, Kalama 200, undated (Box 116)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica: Bibliography of Pope: my contribution, undated (Box 116)
  - Concordance Review, 1974 (Box 116)
  - June 11th: NHI Gathering, undated (Box 116)
  - Address on "Current Developments in English", 1989 Sep (Box 116)
  - Roemer film on dying, undated (Box 116)
  - Shakespearean Comedy: Report to Renaissance Council, 1968 (Box 116)
  - Smith College Poetry Lecture, 1958-1977 (Box 116)
  - Made-Up T.P. Works of 1735 with Prose Tracts and Unrecorded Advertisements, undated (Box 116)
  - Pope's Poetry and Homer's, undated (Box 116)
  - Homer: Pope's Progress With, 1953 (Box 116)
  - Pope: Text of Horace, undated (Box 117)
  - King Lear in Our Time: Reviews, 1972 (Box 117)
  - MLA Presidency and Address, 1969 (Box 117)
  - MM chairmanship: Bulletin, No.1, undated (Box 117)
  - Farewell to Seattle, 1956 (Box 117)
  - Personal: Columbus Day Address, 1954 (Box 117)
  - Alumni Convocation, 1963 (Box 117)
  - WM-EE
    - Othello: Act I [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Oliver Morel [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Books Purchased 1978 (Box 117)
    - E/E [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Othello: Act II [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Norton, 5th Ed. [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Norton: 6th Edition [empty], 1992 (Box 117)
    - First Editions Collections [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Othello: Act V [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Othello: Act III [empty], undated (Box 117)
  - Lumley, Tom [empty], undated (Box 117)
  - Norton, 6th Editions [empty], undated (Box 117)
  - Shrubsole, Lanson [empty], undated (Box 117)
  - Brand Inglis [empty], undated (Box 117)
  - WM EE
    - Norton: Teachers' Manual [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Preface to WM, 6th: Ideas [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - WM - EE: Africa [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Salute to Pope: Yale Lecture Publications Essay [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Columbia Othello [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Nebraska Coll. et. al. Shakespeare Essays [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Soweosone Chester [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - John Bull of Oferdeen [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - College English Advisory [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Swift: Tale [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Ch. 1: Rough Copy [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - AP Geogrphy: Chapter 2 rough copy [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Images of Man [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - WM-EE: India [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - WM-EE: China, undated (Box 117)
    - WM-EE: Japan [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - WM-EE: Africa and Caribbean [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - WM-EE: Middle East [empty], undated (Box 117)
    - Native American [empty], undated (Box 117)
  - MM: Misc. Writings [empty], undated (Box 117)
  - Unfiled Shakespeare, undated (Box 117)
  - Shakespeare Possibilities (print), undated (Box 117)
  - Shakespeare Possibilities (my notes), undated (Box 117)
  - Research
    - Research Assistance, undated (Box 118)
  - Othello: Dallas and New Orleans, 1977 (Box 118)
  - Othello, 1988-1990 (Box 118)
  - Othello's Character, 1990-1992 (Box 118)
  - Igor's Character (empty), undated (Box 118)
  - Desdemona's Character, undated (Box 118)
  - NHC Report on Shakespearean Tragedy, undated (Box 118)
  - Notes on the Humanities, 1986 (Box 118)
  - Humanities Lecture, 1982
    - NHRA Speech, undated (Box 119)
  - Humanities Lecture
    - [Hpoel?] 30: Talk by MM, undated (Box 119)
  - P-H Ed. Book: Planning
    - P-H Book Ed. Selections 9th, 1971 (Box 119)
    - P-H Ed-Book Project, 1971 (Box 119)
  - P-H: Ed. Book: Structure
    - Ed. Book: Planning and Structure, 1972 (Box 120)
    - Resources: Book Ed. Project, 1972 (Box 120)
    - MS Draft - Mack, undated (Box 120)
    - Original - Mack, undated (Box 120)
    - P-H Ed. Book Selections 10th [empty], undated (Box 120)
    - P-H Ed. Book Selections 11th (via), undated (Box 120)
    - Resource: Plays, undated (Box 120)
    - P-H Ed. Book Selections 12th, undated (Box 120)
    - Ed. Book Resources: Stories, Poems, Plays, Etc., undated (Box 120)
  - P-H Ed. Book: 9th Grade
    - 9 Man and Nature, The World That We Feel, undated (Box 120)
    - 9 Man and Man: The Splendid Trap, undated (Box 120)
    - 9 Man and Society, Heroes and Villians, undated (Box 120)
    - 9 Man and Self: The Bundle and the Knot, undated (Box 120)
  - P-H Ed. Book: 10th Grade
    - 10 Man and Nature: The Infinite Book, undated (Box 121)
    - 10 Man and Society: Behold, the Drummer, undated (Box 121)
    - 10 Man and Man: Lifestyles and Way of Life, undated (Box 121)
    - 10 Man and Self: Who are you?, undated (Box 121)
  - P-H Ed. Book: 11th Grade
    - 11 Man and Nature: Of These I Sing, undated (Box 121)
    - 11 Man and Society: Frustration and [Friends?], undated (Box 121)
    - 11 Man and Man: the Artificial Plague, undated (Box 121)
    - 11 Man and Self: Success and Failure, undated (Box 121)
  - P-H Ed. Book: 12th Grade
    - 12 Man and Nature: With Eye or Eyeglass?, undated (Box 121)
    - 12 Man and Society: Each in His Prison, undated (Box 121)
    - 12 Man and Man: The Little Raft, undated (Box 121)
    - 12 Man and Self: Reality and Illusion, undated (Box 121)
  - Humanities, 1979-1989; 4 (Box 122)
  - Humanities: Miscellaneous [folders 1,2], 1963-1977; 2 (Box 122)
  - Humanities: miscellaneous [folder 3], 1963-1977 (Box 123)
  - Ideas and Plans: Humanities, undated (Box 123)
  - Humanities (General), 1970-1977; 2 (Box 123)
  - Humanities (General) Houston, undated (Box 123)
  - 1970s Literary Theory: Structuralists and [French?], 1981-1988 (Box 124)
  - Psychoanalytic Criticism, 1975 (Box 124)
  - Travel Information [folders 1-3], 1980-1992 (Box 124)
  - Travel information [folders 4-6] (Box 125)
  - Norton: 1 vol, CM; 1 vol, WM, 1973-1976 (Box 125)
  - Shoestring Press Series, 1974 (Box 125)
  - Jokes: Humor, 1977 (Box 125)
  - Farewell, undated (Box 125)
  - Hayden, 1968-1985 (Box 125)
  - Talent Lists, 1976-1977 (Box 126)
  - Phase 2, 1977 (Box 126)
  - Smith College: Drew Professorship, 1971 (Box 126)
  - MM Bibliography, undated (Box 126)
  - MM Publications: General, 1977 (Box 126)
  - MLA: Possible Address, 1970 (Box 126)
  - Education in General, 1973 (Box 126)
  - Address to Freshmen, 1960 (Box 126)
  - The Psychological-Educational Revolution, 1969-1973 (Box 127)
  - Miscellaneous printed, 1970; 2 (Box 127)
  - Miscellaneous printed and notes, 1970; 4 (Box 128)
  - Understanding Poetry by Cleanth Brooks and Robert Penn Warren, annotated, 1938-1974, undated (Box 140)
  - Mack Papers, undated; 8 (Box 129)
  - Card Files
    - Principles of Drama Bibliography I, undated (Box 130)
    - Principles of Drama Bibliography II, undated (Box 130)
  - Slides and microfilm (Box 131)
  - Slides and microfilm (Box 132)
  - Book Announcement, undated (Box 133 Broadside)
  - Unidentified film (Box 134 Cold Storage)
  - Unidentified film (Box 135 Cold Storage)
  - Unidentified film (Box 136 Cold Storage)
  - Unidentified film (Box 137 Cold Storage)
  - Unidentified film (Box 138 Cold Storage)
  - Unidentified film (Box 139 Cold Storage)